#Encodergasm Presents
～
I'm gonna go look.
（スパイク）捜しに行く
What?
（ジェット）何っ？
I'm gonna look for my woman.
（スパイク）俺は俺の女をな
あんたは そっちの女を捜せばいい
You can look for that other woman.
Are you dating Julia behind my back?
（スパイク）
俺に内緒でジュリアとデートか？
I feel like I'm in a confessional...
（フェイ）
なあんか ざんげ室にいるみたい
あんた 牧師の経験ある？
Have you ever had experience as a minister?
You were always the one leaving others out of the loop.
（ビシャス）
抜け駆けは お前の専門だったな
この間の決着が まだだぜ
We still haven't settled the score from earlier.
Any time.
いつでも
Lin!
（スパイク）リン！
Hey, out of the way, Lin!
（スパイク）おい どけ！ リン
Lin...
リン…
んはっ！
I was in the same unit as Vicious on Titan.
（グレン）僕とビシャスは
タイタンの同じ部隊にいた
You said that you didn't need comrades...
君は“仲間なんて
いらない”って言ったけど―
...but I'm attracted to that word.
僕は同志って言葉にひかれるんだ
To the point of tears...
涙が出るほどにね
タイタンでは誰もが同志だった
On Titan, we were all comrades...
（グレン）何て曲？
What song is that?
Julia...
（ビシャス）ジュリア
いい曲だな
That's a good tune.
Would you mind if I played that tune on my sax when I go home after all this?
国に帰ったら その曲
サックスで吹いてもいいかな？
After I came home from the war, I was imprisoned.
（グレン）
戦地から帰って 僕は投獄された
They suspected that I was a spy.
スパイの容疑で
ビシャスが証言したと聞かされたよ
I heard that Vicious testified against me.
In prison, I went insane from insomnia.
刑務所で僕は眠れずに
精神をやられて―
As a result, I became a drug addict.
薬漬けになった
その副作用さ
There were side effects.
ホルモンのバランスが崩れて
こうなった
My hormonal balance went out of whack, and this is what happened.
You're the second person to know Vicious since I arrived here...
ここに来て―
ビシャスを知ってる人間に
会ったのは 君が２人目だ
こんな話をするのも
...and the second that I've talked about this to.
Why are you going to see Vicious?
何でビシャスと会うの？
Didn't you just say that he framed you?
あなた ビシャスに
はめられたんじゃないの？
それを確かめたいんだ
I want to see if he really did.
死ぬわよ
You're going to die.
I'm not afraid to die.
死ぬのは怖くない
You're lying.
うそ
どのみち長くないんだ
Either way, I won't last much longer.
Why did you bring me here?
（フェイ）
どうして私を連れてきたの？
Perhaps I wanted to be with someone...
（グレン）
誰かと一緒にいたかったのかも
しれないな
You selfishly help people, and bring them along...
人のこと勝手に助けたり
連れてきたりしといて―
...and then you go off to die?
自分は死にに行くの？
Are you sure it was this woman?
（ジェット）
確かに この女だったんだな？
Yeah...  It's been 6 months since I last saw a woman in the flesh...
（バーテン）ああ　生身の女を
見たのは半年ぶり
...and 2 years since I saw someone that good-looking.
極上の女ってことでいえば
２年ぶりだ
Of course I wouldn't make a mistake!
見間違えるわけないでしょう？
I never wanna live in this town.
この町には住みたかねえな
She sat there, and was talking to Gren.
（バーテン）あそこに座って
グレンと話してた
Julia always sat in that seat, too.
ジュリアも
いつも あの席だったよ
ジュリア？
Julia?
（バーテン）２年前に突然 現れて
ひと月もしないで姿を消した
She suddenly wandered in 2 years ago, and disappeared before a month passed.
どんな女だった？
What kinda woman was she?
She was a real babe.
いい女だったよ
I'm the only one that can keep you alive...
（ビシャス）
お前を生かせるのは俺だけだ
...and I'm the only one that can kill you.
お前を殺せるのもな
I'm only watching a dream that I never awakened from.
（スパイク）俺は ただ
覚めない夢を見てるだけさ
It's like I am watching a dream...
（ジュリア）
まるで夢でも見てるみたい
Be careful when you're with that woman.
（ビシャス）あの女には気をつけろ
Women are all liars...
（ジュリア）
女はみんな うそつきなのよ
When this is over, I'm getting out of all this.
（スパイク）これが終わったら
俺は足を洗う
And then... will you come with me?
そしたら 俺と一緒に…
Are you going to betray me?
（ビシャス）俺を裏切るつもりか？
They're going to kill you.
（ジュリア）あなた 殺されるわ
やっと起きた　寝過ぎよ ３日も
Oh, you're finally up.
You've slept too much.  It's been three days.
Your left eye and right eye are different colors.
（ジュリア）
左右の瞳の色が違うのね
My left eye sees the past.
（スパイク）
この左の目は過去を見てるんだ
（ジュリア）じゃあ 右の目は？
Then what about your right eye?
I'm not dead...
死んじゃいねーよ
Which way is west?
西は どっちだ？
Thanks.
ありがとよ
Tranquilizer, huh?  They're mocking me.
麻酔とは なめられたもんだな
うっ う…
Sorry, but can I ask ya something?
（ジェット）すまねえ
ちょっと聞きたいんだが
オルランドーっていう
ブルーのアパートは？
Where is a blue apartment building called Orlando?
Don't ask me!  I don't know anything!
（男）
俺に聞くな　俺は何も知らん
Um, come on...
（ジェット）いやー あのな…
I want nothing to do with foreigners from now on...
よそ者とは金輪際
関わりたくねんだ
聞いてるだけじゃねえか
I'm just asking!
I'm gonna go find an honest job...
まっとうな仕事でも見つけるさ
What the hell?
何なんだ？
（ジェット）ううっ ああーっ
It's HERE...
ここに あるじゃねえか
Hey!
おい！ おい しっかりしろ
Hey, get it together!
ジェット？
Jet?
何やってんだ？ お前
What the hell are you doing?
What's all this about?
こりゃ 何か？
そういう趣味の男だったわけか？
He was one of THOSE kinds of guys?
What are you saying?
何 言ってんの
グレンは そんなんじゃないわよ
Gren... isn't like that.
Gren?
グレン？
“マンガンの裏ドラ”っと
"Mangan", with "ura-dora"...
He's using an ancient code...
古い暗号 使ってやがる
ジュリアは いた　この町に
Julia was here... in this town.
Yo.
（ジェット）よう
Yeah?
Got anything?
（ジェット）収穫は？
None.
（スパイク）ねーよ
I got something good.
（ジェット）いいネタがある
Catch 'em yourself.
（スパイク）自分で捕まえろ
例のコードネームジュリアの男だぜ
I know about the guy from that code name "Julia".
グレンて野郎だ
そいつは脱獄囚でな
It's a guy named Gren.
He's an escaped convict, and has a hefty bounty on his head.
結構な賞金が懸かってる
If you catch him, I'll let you back on.
そいつを捕まえたら―
戻ってきてもいいぞ
（グレン）もしもし
Hello?
I'm overhead.
（ビシャス）お前の上にいる
一番 空に近いビルの屋上に来い
Come to the roof of the building closest to the sky.
I'll send a woman over.
（グレン）女が渡しに行く
I don't care...
（ビシャス）構わんさ
お前にも会いたかったがな
Although I would have liked to see you as well...
You broke the Bebop, but kept the Swordfish and Hammerhead mobile.
（ジェット）
ビバップを壊しておきながら
ソードフィッシュも―
ハンマーヘッドも
動ける状態のままだったのは―
Did you leave that message so that we'd come find you?
“捜しに来い”っていう
メッセージだったのか？
You've got to be kidding.
（フェイ）ばか言わないでよ
Were you just testing us?
試したんじゃないのか？
Why did you come here?
（フェイ）何で来たの？
I want my money back.
（ジェット）金 返せ
The safe...
金庫
（ジェット）ああ？
...only had 20,000 in it.
（フェイ）
２万しか入ってなかったけど
Is that so?
そうだったか？
Dummy.
（フェイ）おとぼけ
Hey...  Who is Julia?
ねえ ジュリアって何なの？
Dunno... but she has something to do with Spike.
（ジェット）さあな
ただ スパイクと訳ありの女らしい
That's all I know.
それしか知らん
ふうん
～
Souvenir, souvenir, is it here yet?
（エド）お土産 お土産
まだですかー？
It has an EX+ ranking.  It's real.
（リン）ランクはＥＸプラス
本物です
Hand it over.
渡せ
This is the Titan Opal that you requested.
ご希望のタイタンオパールです
Give Gren my regards.
グレンに よろしく伝えてくれ
You saved me from that scorpion back then...
（グレン）あのときも
サソリから助けておいて―
あなたは僕を売った
...yet you sold me out.
Gren?
グレン
久しぶり
Long time no see.
What are you up to?
（ビシャス）何のまねだ？
You gave me that music box because you...
（グレン）あのオルゴールを
僕にくれたのは―
僕なら中を開けて調べたりしないと
思ったから？
...never thought I'd take it apart and examine it?
You found the transmitter...
通信機を見つけたか
Julia was the one who found it.
（グレン）
見つけたのはジュリアだ
あなたから もらったと聞いて
ジュリアは気付いたんだ
She realized as soon as she heard it was a gift from you.
（ビシャス）それが どうした？
And what about it?
あなたは
また僕を殺そうとしたの？
Are you trying to kill me again?
We fought in the war together.  We were comrades.
あなたは戦友だった
同志だった
We fought together on that desert battlefield.
一緒に戦ったんだ
砂漠の戦場で
I looked up to you.
憧れてた
I believed in you.
あなたを信じてた
信じるものなどない
There is nothing there to believe.
信じる必要も
Nor is there a need to believe.
Sir Vicious!
ビシャス様！
In this world... there is nothing to believe in.
この世に信じるものなど…
Vicious!
ビシャス！
Lin's soul won't be saved since he lost his life protecting someone like you!
お前みたいなやつを守って
命を落としたんじゃ―
リンも救われねえ！
I'm not what he was protecting!
やつが守ったのは私ではない
He protected the rules!
おきてだ！
You're in the way!
邪魔だ
（せき）
Hey!  Come on, get a grip!
（スパイク）
おい しっかりしろ　おい！
Hey!
ジュリアは どこにいる？
どこに行った？
Where is Julia?  Where did she go?!
Do you know her?
彼女を知ってるの？
あいつは今 どこにいる？
Where is she now?
（せき）
（グレン）ううっ
内臓をやられてるな
He hit some vital organs.
Shit, would an ambulance come to a place like this?
くそー 救急車なんて来るのか？
こんな所に
もう一度
ポッドに乗せてくれないか？
Can you lift me up into the pod again?
（スパイク）えっ？
I want to go to Titan...
（グレン）タイタンに行きたいんだ
（スパイク）
その体で もつわけないだろ！
時間が かかり過ぎる
You can't possibly last in your condition!
It would take too long!
I won't last long anyway...
（グレン）
どうせ もう長くないんだ
Dying during the voyage would be a good way to go.
旅の途中で死ぬのもいいさ
I want to return there... one more time.
もう一度 戻りたいんだ　あそこへ
I want to be as close as I can.  Please...
少しでも近くへ
お願いだ
そうか
I see.
あなたがスパイク
You are Spike.
Julia was always talking about you...
ジュリアが いつも話してた
...that your two eyes were of different colors.
“瞳の色が一つずつ違う”って
そう言ってた
That's what she said...
...that you get a strange feeling when you look into his eyes.
“目を合わせると
不思議な気持ちになる”って
What was she doing?
あいつはどうしてた？
In the corner seat of the bar...
カウンターの隅の席に―
いつも気付かないうちに座ってた
She always sat there while I wasn't paying attention.
She always requested the same song...
いつも同じ曲をリクエストして―
笑ってたよ
...and smiled.
Sadly... smiled.
悲しそうに―
笑ってた
What do you have?
収穫は？
（スパイク）ねーよ
Nothing.
Hurry up and get in.  We're taking off.
（ジェット）
さっさと入れ　出発するぞ
ジュリア…
Julia...
What?
（エド）何が？
Mm... nothing.  Just an adult's idle muttering.
（フェイ）
うん 別に　大人の独り言
Where did all of you guys go?
みんなで どこ行ってきたの？
（フェイ）いい所よ
Someplace good.
エドだけ知らんちん
Ed's the only one left out!
I'll tell you someday.
（フェイ）
そのうち 話したげるわよ
Nah, it's okay, really.
ううん いい　別に
You're not being cute.
（フェイ）かわいくないわね
星が落ちたよ ブル
The star fell, Bull.
（ブル）あれは ただの星ではない
That is no ordinary star.
That is the tear of a warrior.
戦士の涙だ
What is a warrior?
戦士って何？
この星のどこかで戦い果てた者
One who has finished his battle somewhere on this planet.
グレートスピリットを
信じられなかった哀れな魂
A pitiful soul that could not believe in the Great Spirit.
（スパイク）
どうなってるのか この世界
人生 一寸先は闇
"What is going on with this world?"
"In life, darkness looms one inch away from you."
全く世の中 間違ってる
"This world is truly full of mistakes."
こうなりゃ こっちが踏み外し
ドロップアウトな この人生
"In that case, we'll step away from the mainstream..."
"...and lead the life of a dropout."
そんなふうな あなたに贈る
サイケデリックな狂詩曲
A psychedelic rhapsody for someone just like you.
次回「ボヘミアン･ラプソディ」
Next episode: Bohemian Rhapsody.
さあ 君も
一緒に人生 棒に振ってみないか？
Now, won't you waste away your life with us?